europesworld.org 2014-12-11

# Privacy policy | Europe’s World

We, at _Europe’s World_ , are committed to protecting the privacy and security of your visits to this website. This notice provides our policy regarding the nature, purpose, use, and sharing of any information collected via this Web site. The information you provide on this site will be used only for its intended purpose. We never collect information for commercial marketing. Submitting information is strictly voluntary. By doing so, you are giving us your permission to use the information. If you do not want to give us permission to use your information, simply do not provide it. However, not providing certain information may preclude us from providing you with the information or services you desire.

We collect several types of information including:

  * Personal Information
  * Information Collected for Tracking and Customization (Cookies)
  * Automatically Collected Information

Collection and disclosure of information. Personal Information: To ensure we are able to communicate effectively with visitors to our web site, we collect some information that can be directly associated with a specific person. We call this “Personal Information,” and it includes your email address, and certain Automatically Collected Information, including web-analytic information. We collect Personal Information from you when you affirmatively open an account through the registration process. We collect this Personal Information in order to provide you with timely information via e-mail regarding events, resources and issues. We will not make Personal Information available to anyone other than our employees, staff, and agents.

Information Collected for Tracking and Customization (Cookies) A cookie is a small file that a Web site transfers to your computer to allow it to remember specific information about your session while you are connected. Your computer will only share the information in the cookie with the Web site that provided it, and no other Web site can request it. There are two types of cookies, session and persistent. Session cookies last only as long as your Web browser is open. Once you close your browser, the cookie disappears. Persistent cookies store information on your computer for longer periods of time. Debating Europe uses session and persistent cookies however, at no time is your Personal Information, whether stored in persistent cookies or elsewhere, shared with third parties who have no right to that information. If you do not wish to have session or persistent cookies stored on your machine, you can turn them off in your browser. However, this may affect the functioning of this Web site for you.

**Automatically Collected Information**

We collect and store certain technical information about your visit for use in site management and security purposes. This information includes: The Internet domain from which you access our Web site (for example, “xcompany.com” if you use a private Internet access account, or “yourschool.edu” if you connect from an educational domain); The IP address (a unique number for each computer connected to the Internet) from which you access our Web site; The type of browser (e.g., Netscape, Internet Explorer) used to access our site; The operating system (Windows, Unix) used to access our site; The date and time you access our site; The URLs of the pages you visit; Your username, if it was used to log in to the Web site; and If you visited this Web site from another Web site, the URL of the forwarding site. This information is used to help us make our site more useful for you. With this data we learn about the number of visitors to our site and the types of technology our visitors use. Except for authorized law enforcement investigations, no attempts are made to identify individual users or their usage habits. Raw data logs are retained temporarily as required for security and site management purposes only.

**Web Site Security Notice**

For site security purposes and to ensure that this Web service remains available to all users, this computer system employs software programs that monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information. Anyone using this system expressly consents to such monitoring and is advised that if such monitoring reveals evidence of possible abuse or criminal activity, such evidence may be provided to appropriate law enforcement officials. Unauthorized attempts to upload or change information on our servers are strictly prohibited and may be punishable by law.

**Changes to this policy**

We will revise or update this policy if our practices change, or as we develop better ways to keep you informed about them. Please refer to this page for the latest information and the effective date of any changes. If we decide to change this policy, we will post a new policy on our site and change the date at the bottom. Changes to the policy shall not apply retroactively.
